<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="hello">Book Catalogue!</string>
<string name="app_name">Book Catalogue</string>
<string name="menu_insert">Add Book</string>
<string name="menu_delete">Delete Book</string>
<string name="author">Author</string>
<string name="title">Title</string>
<string name="isbn">ISBN</string>
<string name="publisher">Publisher</string>
<string name="date_published">Date Published</string>
<string name="rating">Rating</string>
<string name="bookshelf">Bookshelf</string>
<string name="read">Have you read this book?</string>
<string name="series">Series</string>
<string name="pages">Pages</string>
<string name="confirm_add">Add Book</string>
<string name="nobooks">There are no books in this Bookshelf. Please add some using the menu at the bottom of this screen.</string>
<string name="menu_sort_by_author_expanded">Expand All</string>
<string name="menu_sort_by">Sort By</string>
<string name="menu_sort_by_author_collapsed">Collapse All</string>
<string name="sort_title">Book Catalogue: by Title</string>
<string name="edit_title">Book Catalogue: Edit Book</string>
<string name="menu_insert_isbn">Add by ISBN</string>
<string name="menu_insert_barcode">Add by Barcode</string>
<string name="search">Search</string>
<string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
<string name="confirm_save">Save Book</string>
<string name="nobookshelves">You have not created any bookshelves yet. Please add some using the menu at the bottom of this screen.</string>
<string name="menu_insert_bs">Create Bookshelf</string>
<string name="confirm_add_bs">Add Bookshelf</string>
<string name="menu_bookshelf">Manage Bookshelves</string>
<string name="confirm_save_bs">Save Bookshelf</string>
<string name="menu_delete_bs">Delete Bookshelf</string>
<string name="delete_1st_bs">Cannot Delete the 1st Bookshelf</string>
<string name="bookshelf_label">Bookshelf: </string>
<string name="all_books">All Books</string>
<string name="isbn_found">ISBN Scanned. Searching Internet.</string>
<string name="title_isbn_search">Book Catalogue: ISBN Search</string>
<string name="title_manage_bs">Book Catalogue: Manage Bookshelves</string>
<string name="title_edit_bs">Book Catalogue: Edit Bookshelf</string>
<string name="book_exists">The book you are trying to add already exists. Skipping.</string>
<string name="search_label">Search for Books</string>
<string name="search_hint">Search Author or Title</string>
<string name="book_not_found">The scanned book was not found. You can sometimes find the correct barcode on the inside front cover. Otherwise please enter the details manually.</string>
<string name="series_num">#</string>
<string name="unable_to_connect_google">Unable to Connect to Google Books</string>
<string name="export_data">Export Books</string>
<string name="export_complete">Export (to SDCard) of data complete. </string>
<string name="import_data">Import Books</string>
<string name="import_alert">Warning. Importing data may update existing book records with new information if the id in the import file is the same as an existing id. This is usually fine if you changed a field in an exported file. If you created a new book record, ensure the id field is blank.</string>
<string name="export_failed">ERROR: Export (to SDCard) of data failed. </string>
<string name="import_failed">ERROR: Import of data (from SDCard) failed. Is the file in the correct place?</string>
<string name="search_title">Book Catalogue: Search Results</string>
<string name="results_found">Results Found</string>
<string name="administration_label">Administration</string>
<string name="administration_title">Book Catalogue: Administration</string>
<string name="menu_administration">Admin</string>
<string name="install_scan">To scan your books via the ISBN barcode, you must install the zxing barcode scanner application. Press OK to install, or Cancel to skip.</string>
<string name="install_scan_title">Install Barcode Scanner</string>
<string name="version_number">Version Number</string>
<string name="donate">If you would like to support the development of this application, please donate using a my Amazon Wishlist or the paypal button below. Being in Australia means I cannot publish a &quot;paid&quot; version. :-) </string>
<string name="unable_to_connect_amazon">Unable to Connect to Amazon</string>
<string name="upgrade_title">Since your last upgrade</string>
<string name="edit_book">Edit Book</string>
<string name="edit_book_notes">Your Comments</string>
<string name="edit_book_friends">Loan Book</string>
<string name="unknown_error">An unknown error occured</string>
<string name="notes">Notes</string>
<string name="loaned_to">This book has been loaned to:</string>
<string name="nobody">Nobody</string>
<string name="loan_to">Loan book to:</string>
<string name="returned">Returned</string>
<string name="name">Name</string>
<string name="webpage_label">Webpage</string>
<string name="sourcecode_label">Source Code</string>
<string name="contact_label">Contact</string>
<string name="webpage">http://wiki.github.com/eleybourn/Book-Catalogue/</string>
<string name="sourcecode">http://github.com/eleybourn/Book-Catalogue</string>
<string name="contact">eleybourn@gmail.com</string>
<string name="donate_label">Donate</string>
<string name="about_label">About this App</string>
<string name="administration_functions_label">Functions</string>
<string name="sortby_popup_title">Sort By</string>
<string name="sortby_author">Sort by Author</string>
<string name="sortby_title">Sort by Title</string>
<string name="sortby_series">Sort by Series</string>
<string name="sortby_loan">Sort by Loaned</string>
<string name="sortby_unread">Sort by Unread</string>
<string name="list_price">List Price</string>
<string name="date_started_reading">Date Started Reading</string>
<string name="date_finished_reading">Date Finished Reading</string>
<string name="update_thumbnails">Update Thumbnails</string>
<string name="overwrite_thumbnail">Do you want to overwrite all existing thumbnails. Warning, this may take a long time. </string>
<string name="yes">Yes</string>
<string name="no">No</string>
<string name="ok">OK</string>
<string name="download_thumbs">Thumbnails are being downloaded in the background</string>
<string name="search_fail">Searching for the book failed. Please check your network settings.</string>
<string name="menu_delete_thumb">Delete Thumbnail</string>
<string name="help">Help</string>
<string name="filler_help_text">Full online application help will come soon. </string>
<string name="menu_manage_fields">Manage Field Visibility</string>
<string name="manage_fields_help">Selected fields are visible in the add/edit book screens. Unselected fields are hidden.</string>
<string name="edit_book_anthology">Anthology Titles</string>
<string name="amazon_wishlist">Amazon Wishlist</string>
<string name="same_author">All stories in this anthology are written by the same author</string>
<string name="menu_delete_anthology">Delete Title from Anthology</string>
<string name="is_anthology">Is this book an Anthology?</string>
<string name="populate_anthology_titles">Automatically Populate Titles (EXPERIMENTAL)</string>
<string name="automatic_population_failed">Automatic Population of Titles Failed</string>
<string name="anthology">Anthology</string>
<string name="anthology_confirm">Please confirm that these anthology titles are (mostly) correct</string>
<string name="anthology_save">Save</string>
<string name="anthology_add">Add</string>
<string name="menu_add_thumb_photo">Add Thumbnail from Camera</string>
<string name="thumbnail">Cover Thumbnail</string>
<string name="menu_rotate_thumbnail">Rotate Thumbnail</string>
<string name="help_title_nutshell">In a Nutshell</string>
<string name="help_text_nutshell">Book Catalogue is exactly what it sounds like; a simple application that allows you to create a list of all your books. Books can be added either manually, by ISBN, or by barcode. This is an open source android application - for more information please visit </string>
<string name="help_text_nutshell2">http://wiki.github.com/eleybourn/Book-Catalogue/</string>
<string name="help_title_home">Home Screen</string>
<string name="help_text_home1">The bulk of this screen lists your entire book collection. By default your books will be sorted by Author. If you click on the</string>
<string name="help_text_home2">icon it will expand to display all books for that author and a small tick to show if you have read the book or not. You can change the sort order by selecting </string>
<string name="help_text_home3">from the menu, which will provide 5 options; sort by author, title, series, loaned and read/unread. </string>
<string name="help_text_home4">When you quit, Book Catalogue will remember all your current settings, including how it is sorted, current bookshelf, and which book you are focused on.</string>
<string name="help_text_home5">Other display options under menu include</string>
<string name="help_text_home6">which will expand all authors (or series / loans depending on your sort setting). This option is not available when sorting by title.</string>
<string name="help_text_home7">If you long click on a book title (not author name) it will bring up a context menu which will allow you to delete a book or open/edit a book at a specific tab.</string>
<string name="help_title_bookshelves">Bookshelves</string>
<string name="help_text_bookshelves1">At the top of the main screen is the bookshelf selector.</string>
<string name="help_text_bookshelves2">This will tell you which bookshelf you are currently viewing and, if you click on it, allow you to change the current bookshelf.</string>
<string name="help_text_bookshelves3">There is a special bookshelf called “All Books” which allows you to display all books in the database regardless of the bookshelf they are in.</string>
<string name="help_title_addbooks">Adding Books</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooks1">From the menu you can choose to add a book in one of three methods</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooks2">1. By Barcode</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooks3">2. By ISBN</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooks4">3. Manually</string>
<string name="help_title_addbooksbarcode">Adding Books by Barcode</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode1">You must have the</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode1a">zxing</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode2">barcode scanner installed to use this function.</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode3">If you point the camera at the barcode (ISBN) on the back of the book it will scan and start searching the Internet to try and automatically populate the fields. Please be aware that there is also a situation where the barcode is an older UPC number, in this case while it looks like an ISBN it is not. You will most often find these in older trade/pulp books. Another clue for these is if they have a barcode on the inside cover. The inside barcode is the the isbn barcode and will scan/search correctly.</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode4">That is actually a rather large issue with ISBN’s. For full info have a read of</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksbarcode4a">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number</string>
<string name="help_title_addbooksisbn">Adding Books by ISBN</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksisbn1">Books published in the 70’s and early 80’s may have an ISBN but not a barcode. In this situation you can type in the ISBN from the back of the book and it will, once again, search the internet for information regarding the book. ISBN’s can either be a 13 digit ISBN or a 10 digit ISBN, where only the first three and last characters are different. In this situation both are correct and will return the correct search.</string>
<string name="help_title_addbooksmanual">Adding Books Manually</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksmanual1">If you have a book without a barcode or ISBN or a book that is not available in Google Books or Amazon than you will need to add the book manually. Fill in as many fields as appropriate. The fields on this page will be pre-populated if you have successfully added a book via barcode or ISBN.</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksmanual2">Note: depending on which field you have set to be visible (see Field Visibility under Administration) you will see different fields to this screenshot.</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksmanual3a">The Author, Series and Publisher fields will try and suggest options based on existing books. Once complete, click on the</string>
<string name="help_text_addbooksmanual3b">button at the bottom of the screen. This will automatically refresh the screen adding additional tabs to the top and allowing you to fill in more details.</string>
<string name="help_title_editbooks">Editing Books</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooks1">There are up to 4 tabs available when editing a book. Book Details, Your Comments, Loan Book and Anthology Titles.</string>
<string name="help_title_editbooksedit">Editing Books – Edit Book</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksedit1">This is the same screen as “add book”. The only difference is the “Anthology” checkbox; which will activate/deactivate the anthology tab. You also have more options to modify the book thumbnail. If you long hold on the thumbnail you will get a menu with four options.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksedit2">1. “Delete Thumbnail” will remove the saved thumbnail from the database. This is useful if the wrong thumbnail was automatically downloaded.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksedit3">2. “Add Thumbnail from Gallery” allows you to use a photo from your gallery as a thumbnail. </string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksedit4">3. “Add Thumbnail from Camera” allows you to take a photo of the book cover to use as a thumbnail. It assumes the book is in portrait orientation. Which brings us to...</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksedit5">4. “Rotate Thumbnail” if the book cover is in the wrong orientation this will rotate the cover 90 degrees clockwise. You may need to do this several times to get it to the correct orientation.</string>
<string name="help_title_editbookscomments">Editing Books – Your Comments</string>
<string name="help_text_editbookscomments1a">This tab is to enter any personal information regarding this book; these are fields such as have you read the book, your rating, any notes, is your copy signed, etc. Press</string>
<string name="help_text_editbookscomments1b">to save your changes</string>
<string name="help_title_editbooksloan">Editing Books – Loan Book</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksloan1">This screen allows you to record who you have loaned a book to. This, in combination with “Sort by Loan” is useful to keep track of people who have your books. The Name field will try and suggest people based on existing your contact list.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksloan2">Once a book has been returned you simply press the “Returned” button to mark it as returned.</string>
<string name="help_title_editbooksanthology">Editing Books – Anthology Titles</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology1">If your book is an anthology of stories, this will let you store the titles of each story in the book.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology2">Select the checkbox at top of the screen is all of the stories in the anthology are written by the primary author. This will save space on the screen and remove the author field from the add section below. You can add as many titles as you want by typing them in the boxes at the bottom of the screen.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology3a">Each new title will appear at the bottom of the list, though using the</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology3b">buttons you can move a title up or down in the list. If you want to edit a title, just click on it and it will appear in the fields at the bottom, and the “Add” button will change to a “Save” button. To delete a title, just long click on it and a context menu will appear with the delete option.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology4">There is an experimental function to try and automatically populate the anthology titles. Simply click on the menu button and the option will appear.</string>
<string name="help_text_editbooksanthology5">This will only work about 50% of the time, and may not be 100% correct in that case. If it finds any it will confirm the titles before they get saved into the database.</string>
<string name="help_title_admin">Help and Admin</string>
<string name="help_text_admin1a">In the main menu (on the book list screen) you can select</string>
<string name="help_text_admin1b">to goto the administration screen. There are 4 tabs available Help (this information), Administration, Donate and About this App.</string>
<string name="help_title_adminadmin">Administration</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin1">There are 5 links on the Administration page; Manage Bookshelves, Manage Field Visibility, Export Books, Import Books, Update Thumbnails.</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin2">Manage Bookshelves</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin3">You can add/edit/delete the list of bookshelves from the Manage Bookshelves page. The “Add” button is from the menu, click on the bookshelf title to edit or long click on the title to delete.</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin4">Manage Field Visibility</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin5">As more and more people have requested fields it the screen became full of fields that many people weren’t using. Unchecking a field allows you to hide it from the list and edit screen. This also includes the cover thumbnail.</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin6">Export Books</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin7">You can export your complete collection to a csv file on the sdcard. This will create a file called bookCatalogue/export.tab which can be loaded and manipulated in excel. The thumbnails are stored in the same location.</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin8">Import Books</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin9">If you have modified the bookCatalogue/export.tab file, you can load it back into the database (including all bookshelves, loans and anthology titles).</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin10">Be warned: If the id in the import file is the same as an existing id, importing data will update existing book records with new information. This is usually fine if you changed a field in an exported file. If you created a new book record, ensure the id field is blank.</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin11">Update Thumbnails</string>
<string name="help_text_adminadmin12">This will search the internet for thumbnails of any of your books with an ISBN. You can search for thumbnails for all books, or only books without a current thumbnail. Be warned: this function can take a long time.</string>
<string name="help_title_admindonate">Donate</string>
<string name="help_text_admindonate1a">If you like this app, it would be great if you could donate to support me, the developer. This page links to my</string>
<string name="help_text_admindonate1b">as well as my paypal donate page.</string>
<string name="help_text_admindonate2">Being in Australia means I cannot publish a paid version.</string>
<string name="help_title_adminabout">About this App</string>
<string name="help_text_adminabout1">This screen will show you the current version of the Book Catalogue you are running as well as links to the app homepage, source code and my email address.</string>
<string name="signed">Has this book been signed</string>
<string name="audiobook">Audiobook</string>
<string name="read_start">Date started reading</string>
<string name="read_end">Date finished reading</string>
<string name="location">Location of the book</string>
<string name="duplicate_title">Duplicate Book</string>
<string name="duplicate_alert">The book you are trying to add already exists in the database, are you sure you want to add another copy</string>
<string name="menu_add_thumb_gallery">Add Thumbnail from Gallery</string>
<string name="backup_request">Would you like to backup your database to your sdcard</string>
<string name="backup_title">Backup?</string>
<string name="searching_google_books">Searching Google Books</string>
<string name="searching_amazon_books">Searching Amazon</string>
<string name="bookshelf_title">Select bookshelves for this book</string>
<string name="bookshelves">Select Bookshelves</string>
<string name="format">Format</string>
<string name="paperback">Paperback</string>
<string name="hardcover">Hard Cover</string>
<string name="ebook">eBook</string>
<string name="guide">Guide / Companion</string>
<string name="description">Description</string>
<string name="genre">Genre</string>
</resources>
